James Pritts

Web-page · Scholar · Github · Linkedin

□ jbpritts@fb.com **□** +1 512 650 8293

Research Interests

My research is on robust multi-model estimation and minimal solvers with applications to geometric camera auto-calibration, scene-plane rectification and modeling repeated scene content. The goal of future work is to extend these methods to applications in visual localization and feature matching.

Education

Czech Technical University, Prague, Czechia PhD candidate, Computer Science Thesis: "Methods for the Rectification of Imaged Coplanar Repeated Patterns"	2020
Czech Technical University, Prague, Czechia MSc, Computer Science, with honors	2013
The University of North Texas, Denton, TX	2002

Experience

BSc, Mathematics

Facebook Reality Labs, AR/VR, Pittsburgh PA	2019 – Present
Post-Doctoral Research Scientist	
Responsible for developing methods for the geometric calibration and auto-calibration	
of head-mounted capture systems.	

BAE Systems, Advanced Information Technologies, Burlington, MA

Lead Software Engineer

2003 – 2008

Led teams to develop state-of-the-art computer-vision based defense systems. Managed relations with government customers and contractors by serving as the point of contact. Conducted successful program demos and reviews.

NASA, Johnson Space Center, Houston, TX Researcher Developed a see health to the desirent technology for the group of a set the control line the

Developed new body tracking technology for the purpose of remotely controlling the robotic arm of the International Space Station.

Publications

- Y. Lochman, O. Dobosevych, R. Hryniv, and J. Pritts. Minimal solvers for single-view auto-calibration. In WACV (accepted), 2021
- **J. Pritts**, Z. Kukelova, V. Larsson, Y. Lochman, and O. Chum. Minimal solvers for rectifying from radially-distorted conjugate translations. *IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence*, 2020
- **J. Pritts**, Z. Kukelova, V. Larsson, Y. Lochman, and O. Chum. Minimal solvers for rectifying from radially-distorted scales and change of scales. *Int. J. Comput. Vis.*, 128(4):950–968, 2020
- **J. Pritts**, Z. Kukelova, V. Larsson, and O. Chum. Rectification from radially-distorted scales. In ACCV, 2018
- ${\bf J.~Pritts},~{\rm Z.~Kukelova},~{\rm V.~Larsson},~{\rm and~O.~Chum.}~{\rm Radially\text{-}distorted~conjugate~translations}.$ In CVPR,~2018
- **J. Pritts**, D. Rozumnyi, M. P. Kumar, and O. Chum. Coplanar repeats by energy minimization. In BMVC, 2016

- J. Pritts, O. Chum, and J. Matas. Detection, rectification and segmentation of coplanar repeated patterns. In CVPR, 2014
- J. Pritts, O. Chum, and J. Matas. Approximate models for fast and accurate epipolar geometry estimation. In IVCNZ, 2013

Awards

Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV) 2018 Saburo Tsuji Best Paper Award	2018
Image and Vision Computing New Zealand (IVCVNZ) 2013 Best Paper Award	2013
Dean's Prize for Outstanding Master's Thesis, CTU in Prague	2013

Academic Activities

Reviewer for ECCV, 3DV

Programming Skills

Python, MATLAB, C++

Invited Talks

Opportunities and Risks of Artificial Intelligence The Aspen Institute's 2018 Young Leader's Program, Tále, Slovakia	03/2018
Radially Distorted Conjugate Translations Ukrainian Catholic University Data Science Colloquium, Lviv, Ukraine	12/2017
Detection, Rectification, and Segmentation of Coplanar Repeated Patterns The Eastern European Computer Vision Conference, Odessa, Ukraine	07/2017
Visual Recognition in the Wild: Image Retrieval, Faces, and Text The Eastern European Computer Vision Conference, Odessa, Ukraine	07/2016
Detection, Rectification and Segmentation of Coplanar Repeated Patterns The 34th Pattern Recognition and Computer Vision Colloquium, Prague, Czechia	04/2014
aching	

Teac

Image Retrieval Instructor - Master's level, Ukrainian Catholic University	2017 - 2018
Pattern Recognition and Machine Learning, AE4B33RPZ TA - Bachelor's level, Czech Technical University in Prague	2013 - 2016